Adarsh R

Embedded Developer

Address 2nd floor,#44, 10th cross, Maruthi Nagar, BTM - I

Bengaluru, 560029

+91 96 50 562383

adarsh@outlook.in **Email** Web https://adarsh.online

Summary

A curious Embedded developer with 4 years experience on IoT, Web & Android apps develpoment. Solid knowledge of MCU's, web & cloud technologies. Detail oriented, Dedicated and Dependable team player who has strong analytical, organizational, probem solving, presentation, communication and project management skills. Also who posess ability to manage multiple tasks and work in a fast paced schedule.

Reference

Phone

Mayank Tyagi

MD - Entrench Electronics

+91 95 99 051728 Email mayank@entrench.in

Technical Expertise

Languages Java, C, Embedded C, Python, PHP, Javascript, Android,

NodeJs, HTML, CSS

Protocols RS-232, I2C, SPI, UART, MQTT, COAP

Database Firebase, NoSQL, MySQL, SQL Server

IDE Android Studio, Eclipse, ATmel Studio. MATLAB, Keil uVission

Vissual Studio



Java

C

NodeJs

Firebase

Embedded C

Android

MuC's and SOC's

PHP, HTML, Javascript, CSS

AWS, Google Cloud

Freelance Developer / Entrench Electronics Pvt. Ltd.

Hardware Design for the need of client. Testing and interfacing the individual I/O Systems. Used GSM, MQTT, CoAP to transfer data with appliances. Developed backend using AWS, Raspberry Pi, NodeMcu, NodeJs, HTML and Javascript. Used various Javascript Libraries like Annyang for voice recognition Used facebook and OpenCV for facial recognition Designed Android App for controlling the system.

Entrench Electronics Pvt. Ltd

2014 - 2017

2017 - NOW

Sr. Embedded Engineer

Work Experience

Lead projects and designed training module of the company Designed Hardwar and software platform of IoT based school management system Converted conventional gas meter using Hall effect sesnor, ATmega8 MUC and SIM900 Designed and developed company's web portal using PHP,HTML and JQuery Designed fire fighting robot using Raspberry pi and thermal camera. Product testing

Times Globacom Pvt. Ltd

2014 - 2014

Sr. Embedded Engineer

Created an interactive training software using Adobe Flash. Managed and supervised a team of junior research engineers. Developed many training modules and projects.

Robosapiens Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

2013 - 2014

Research Engineer

I've developed Android and Cyber Security training modules Wrote product description on compan's ecommmerce portal Providing customer support on Projects purchased through online portal Delivered Training sessions in Primeir Institutes

Education

Bachelor of Electronics and Communication Engineering

2009 - 2013

Anna University, Chennai

Developed gesture controlled robot using Matlab Image Processing and ATmega8. Created self balancing robot using Arduino, accelerometer and gyroscope, Designed a laser communication system.

Projects

Interactive Smart Mirror with Facial Recognition

Platform: Raspberry Pi, Electron, NodeJs Languages: Python, Javascript, Bash Scripting

Brief: To create an interactive smart mirror to act as the base of home automation.

Responsibilities

Wrote electron app using NodeJs
Used Openface library for facial recognition
Used annyang javascript library for voice recognition
Setup MQTT broker on Raspberry Pi
Integrating ESP8266 with RPi using MQTT
Product testing

Clinic Management application

Platform: Raspberry Pi, Firebase, NodeJs Language: Javascript, HTML, JQuery, Python

Brief: To design a complete clinic management system with live token display unit.

Responsibilities

Writing NodeJs app to manage token and registration Printing tokens using thermal Printer Displaying live token using LED Matrix Display Developing back end application using HTML Developing Android app for appointment registration

Smart Gas Meter

Platform: ATmega8, SIM900, Apache

LanguageS: Embedded C, AT Commands, PHP, SQL

Brief: Coverting an analog gas meter to smart meter by adding an extra module.

Responsibilities

Writing Embedded C code for handling halleffect sensor Storing reading in EEPROM Sending Data to server using SIM900 Wrote a program to fetch the data throug sms gateway in PHP

RFID & Biometric Based Attendance System

Platform: Raspberry Pi, ESP8266 Language: Embedded C, Python, PHP

Brief: TO develop an IoT based school management system with multiple user login.

Responsibilities

Interfcaing EM18 RFID reader with ESP8266 Connecting ESP8266 client station using MQTT Wrote Python Flask server to manage the data locally Pushing the data in an intervel through RESTful API Parsing RESTful API in server side uing PHP

I here by declare that all the information mentioned above is true and best of my knowledge